<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: travel | TIL bryant ...]]></title>
  <link href="http://sansmischevia.github.com/blog/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sansmischevia.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-04T10:14:39-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://sansmischevia.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[bryant chou]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[chou.bryant@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Only reason for traveling]]></title>
    <link href="http://sansmischevia.github.com/blog/2012/07/08/best-quote-ever/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-08T23:51:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://sansmischevia.github.com/blog/2012/07/08/best-quote-ever</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>The most beneficial effect of traveling that I’ve found is that it forces you to become more confident and independent in a million, tiny, unnoticeable ways that add up to a great, noticeable whole. The more difficult and exotic the culture, the more it challenges you, the more it engages you on an emotional level, and the more you grow in intangible and personal ways.</p></blockquote>

<p>I lived in India for 4 months in 2007, and when people ask me what it was like living and traveling all around the country for that length of time, I usually respond with something simple because I don't want people to have a bad impression. Responses range from something plain like, "rad", or "wild", to something a bit more catchy, like "sensory overload".</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I have yet to run into a westerner that describes India in a way that I'd want to share with people. I feel like I can't verbalize my experience there in a manner that does that incredible experience justice. The number of emotions, the beautiful sights, mixed in with neverending conflicts of emotions is incredibly hard to describe to someone that has not been to India. But this post over at <a href="http://postmasculine.com/a-dust-over-india">postmasculine.com</a> does an amazing job.</p>

<p>My experience wasn't nearly as difficult as the blogger's but I definitely can relate.</p>

<p>One thing holds true. I've been to 51 out of the 100 places that <a href="http://apps.facebook.com/onehundredplaces/?fb_source=bookmark_apps&amp;ref=bookmarks&amp;count=0&amp;fb_bmpos=2_0">The Travel List Challenge</a> has listed on their facebook app, and India has been the <em>most</em> influencial place I've ever been to. Unfortunately it just <em>may</em> be the boy on the train you stand next to that is coughing up blood, or the bloated stomachs of malnourished babies you see playing in garbage heaps. You leave the country with a different lens on life. You leave confused, distraught, invigorated. India is also one of the most beautiful places in the world. The sights, the sounds, the people, the food... it all comes together and will be an attack on all five of your senses.</p>

<p>But when you experience such extermes of humanity, you have a much better understanding of the norm. India, you're a wretched child, but maybe that's why I love you most.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/boy.jpg" title="boy" alt="boy" />
<img src="/assets/images/kerala.jpg" title="kerala" alt="kerala" />
<img src="/assets/images/shubangan.jpg" title="Hotel Shubangan Rooftop post monsoon" alt="hotel shubangan rooftop post monsoon" /></p>

<p>If you're in your twenties, and you're done going to the same old touristy spots, give India a shot. I promise it'll be worth it.</p>

<h2>Jai Ho!</h2>

<p><a href="http://postmasculine.com/a-dust-over-india">link</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
